Keith Morrow Martin Papers
Keith Morrow Martin Papers
1928-1987
Martin, Keith, 1911-1983.
3.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American painter, collagist; died 1983. Collection includes correspondence (1933-1978); artwork reproductions and photographs; writings, including a reminiscence of Gertrude Stein; and memorabilia, including inventories of artwork, itineraries, photographs, financial material, exhibition announcements, invitations, and catalogs (1931-1987), and articles and reviews about Martin. Correspondence covers family, business, and personal correspondence, including that with Adelyn Breeskin, Tom L. Freudenheim, Henry Gorski, Lincoln F. Johnson, Ralph T. Millet, Wasyl Palijczuk, Charles Parkhurst, Brenda Richardson, Eleanor Patterson Spencer, Bertha Fanning Taylor, and Alice B. Toklas.
149480
Biographical History
Keith Morrow Martin (1911-1983) was an American abstract/surrealist artist and educator. Born in Lincoln, Nebraska, he attended the Art Institute of Chicago and then travelled extensively, spending the early 1930s in Vienna, Paris and Berlin and the early 1940s in Iceland and England. He lived in New York for several years (1937-1941) but for the majority of his career -- 35 years -- resided in Baltimore, Maryland.
Martin's media of choice included collage, pen-and-ink, and mixed media, and his work has been exhibited at the Art Institute of Chicago as well as the Corcoran Gallery, National Academy of Design, Pennsylvania Academy, and Whitney Museum of American Art.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Spanning 1928 to 1987, the Keith Morrow Martin Papers comprises biographical material, family and general correspondence, artwork, writings, and memorabilia of the Nebraska-born artist. Illuminating Martin's experimental artistic style and dominated by a large number of exhibition catalogs, the collection documents both the career and personal life of the painter, collage artist, and educator (1911-1983).
Family correspondence (Boxes 1-2) consists primarily of holograph letters to and from Martin's parents, sister, brother, and cousin, between 1937 and 1978. The General correspondence (Boxes 2-3), incorporating incoming and outgoing letters in chronological sequence, spans the years 1933 to 1978. Many incoming letters are also addressed to David McIntyre, Baltimore Museum of Art assistant director and Martin's companion of 35 years, who authored several outgoing letters on behalf of Martin. Correspondents include regionally and nationally known artists (Yvonne D. Backus, Ruth M. Bernstein, James L. Brown, Robert Bryant, Carolyn Stout Carlson, Gladys Goldstein, Henry Gorski, Tomi Kleff, John Koch, Ralph T. Millet, Wasyl Palijczuk, Virginia Petrick, William Louis Pitts, Liz Whitney Quisgard, Shelby Shackelford, Lillian Shapiro, Bertha Fanning Taylor, Sally Turner, Andy Unger, Ruth Nagle Watkins, Betty Wells, May Wilson, Florence Zavadil); a dancer (Erick Hawkins); musicians (Claire Deene, Gian Carlo Menotti); literary figures (Robert Henkes, Lawrence V. Lynch, Mary Owings Miller, Eleanor Patterson Spencer, Alice B. Toklas); curators and art historians (Adelyn Dohme Breeskin, James W. Foster, Tom L. Freudenheim, Carol V. Harford, Lincoln F. Johnson, Katharine Kuh, Julien Levy, Bates Lowry, David McIntyre, Jane E. Ostryniec, Charles Parkhurst, Brenda Richardson, Gertrude Rosenthal); political figures (William B. Macomber, Joseph D. Tydings); and patrons (Elizabeth Cashen, Robert Wainwright Erickson, Ordella Geisler, David Flierl Guillaume, David Hill, Ross Idol, Stan Mazaroff, Martin Palmer, Louis B. Peters, Otis Taylor, Scout Thirkield, Elizabeth and Edwin Tunis).
Organizations represented include cultural institutions (Academy of the Arts, Art in Embassies Program, Art Institute of Chicago, Artists Association of Nantucket, Ball State Gallery, Baltimore Arts Festival, Baltimore Hebrew Congregation, Baltimore Museum of Art, B. T. Batsford Ltd., Butler Institute of American Art, Chautauqua Art Association, Corcoran Gallery of Art, Denver Art Museum, Ford Foundation, Gallery 100, Honolulu Academy of Arts, Jewish Community Center of Baltimore, Juster Gallery, National Collection of Fine Arts, National Gallery of Art, Nationalgalerie, Norfolk Museum, Oklahoma Printmakers Society, Peale Museum, Phoenix-Chase Galleries, Raydon Galleries, Santa Barbara Museum of Art, Sarasota Art Association, Society of the Four Arts, Tidewater Artists, Tour Gallery, Whitney Museum of American Art); educational institutions (College of Notre Dame of Maryland, Essex Community College, Goucher College, Morgan State College, Western Maryland College); and businesses (Art Consultants of Baltimore, Art Rental Gallery, Container Corporation of America, Miller & Paine, National Brewing Co., Julius Wile Sons and Co.). A selected index to the Correspondence follows the box list.
Artwork (Box 3) encompasses ballet costume designs, original greeting cards for the years 1943 to 1955, photographs, and reproductions. Costume designs for ballet are depicted in programs and periodicals dated 1936 and 1937. Photographs (1931-1969) of murals, paintings, and exhibitions are organized by dates provided by Martin. Arranged chronologically, Reproductions (1935-1973) include greeting cards, safety posters, magazine covers, and an art instruction book.
Statements on painting, a personal reminiscence about Gertrude Stein, overviews of an adult painting class taught by Martin, two published poems, and miscellaneous notes constitu te Writings (Box 3). Memorabilia (Boxes 3-7) includes financial material, itineraries (1967-1977), photographs, printed material, and typescript reviews and additional writings by others (1945-1959). Financial material consists of museum receipts and acceptances (1946-1977) and Martin's partial inventory of his artwork with annotated prices (1945-1977). Photographs of Martin (1928-1978) as well as those with family and friends (1928-1969) are organized by dates provided by him. Printed material contains articles and reviews about Martin (1946-1978), newspaper clippings (1928-1987), exhibition announcements, invitations, and catalogs for group and one-man shows (1931-1987), and one exhibition poster (1945). Literary works by Yves Battistini, Audrey McGaffin, and Julia Randall Sawyer are among the Writings by others.
Arrangement of the Collection
Family correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name. General correspondence is arranged chronologically; a selected index to correspondence is provided at the end of this finding aid. Writings are arranged chronologically also, while Artwork and Memorabilia are arranged alphabetically by type.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Breeskin, Adelyn Dohme, 1896-1986.; Freudenheim, Tom L.; Gorski, Henry.; Johnson, Lincoln F.; Martin, Keith, 1911-1983.; Millet, Ralph T., 1953.; Palijczuk, Wasyl, 1934-; Parkhurst, Charles.; Richardson, Brenda.; Spencer, Eleanor P. (Eleanor Patterson); Stein, Gertrude, 1874-1946.; Taylor, Bertha Fanning.; Toklas, Alice B.; Art, American.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Collage, American.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Articles.; Audiocassettes.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Financial records.; Inventories.; Itineraries.; Photographs.; Reviews (documents); Sound recordings.; Artists.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Keith Morrow Martin.
Costume sketches, gift of Connie Conley, 2021
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 1)
- Family correspondence
  - Kile, Charlotte ("Cousin Lottie"), 1961-1978; undated (Box 1)
  - Martin, Homer V. and Mrs. (parents), 1937-1968; undated; 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Martin, Martha (sister) and friends (Marie Cronley, Isabel Padro), 1937-1977; undated (Box 1)
  - Martin, Richard (brother) and family, 1953-1977 (Box 2)
  - Miscellany (Box 2)
- General correspondence
  - [General], 1933-1978; 10 folders (Box 2)
  - Undated (Box 3)
- Artwork
  - Costume designs for ballet, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
  - Costume designs for ballet, 1936-1937 (Oversize 1)
    Gift of Connie Conley, 2021
  - Greeting cards, original, 1943-1955; undated (Box 3)
  - Photographs
    - [General], 1931-1969; undated (Box 3)
    - Exhibitions at galleries, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Reproductions, 1935-1938; 1947-1970,; 1973,; undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Reproductions, 1942-1944 (Oversize 1)
- Writings
  - [General], 1930-1973 (Box 3)
- Memorabilia
  - Brenda Richardson talks on K.M.M., 25 Sep 1977; 1 audiocassette (Box 3)
  - Museum receipts, acceptances, 1946-1977 (Box 3)
  - Partial inventory of artwork (priced), 1945-1977; undated (Box 3)
  - Itineraries, 1967-1977 (Box 3)
  - Photographs
    - Martin, Keith Morrow, 1928-1978 (Oversize 1)
    - With family and friends, 1928-1969; undated (Box 4)
  - Printed material
    - Articles about, reviews, 1946-1978; undated (Box 4)
    - Clippings, 1928-1987; undated; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Exhibition announcements, invitations
      - Group shows, 1936-1978; undated (Box 4)
      - One-man shows, 1945-1987; undated (Box 5)
    - Exhibition catalogs
      - Group shows, 1931-1957; 6 folders (Box 5)
      - Group shows, 1957-1965; 7 folders (Box 6)
      - Group shows, 1966-1978; undated; 5 folders (Box 7)
      - One-man shows, 1945-1987; undated (Box 7)
    - Exhibition poster - Vendome, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Typescript reviews by others, 1954-1957; undated
  - Writings by others
    - Battistini, Yves, "La saga de Keith 1'Enchanteur", 1945 (Box 7)
    - McGaffin, Audrey, "Scheherazade's Supper", 1959, 1950s? (Box 7)
    - Sawyer, Julia Randall, untitled essay, undated (Box 7)
  - Miscellany (Box 7)
Selected index to correspondence
Academy of the Arts (Easton, Maryland) 1966 Apr. 27 (telegram) 1970 Apr. 7 1974 Apr. 4 1974 Apr. 6 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1976 Aug. 3 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Adams, Virginia Petrick see Petrick, Virginia
Art Consultants of Baltimore 1966 Apr. 20 (re: Center Club exhibition) 1968 Nov. 11 (re: WCBM Art Gallery)
Art in Embassies Program (U. S. Department of State) 1969 July 15 1973 Nov. 28 1977 Oct. 13
Art Institute of Chicago 1947 Nov. 4 1948 Jan. 30 1948 Sept. 28 1948 Oct. 1
Art Rental Gallery (Washington, D. C.) 1958 Mar. 17
Artists Association of Nantucket 1964 Sept. 12
Backus, Yvonne D. 1958 Mar. 4
Ball State Gallery (Muncie, Indiana) 1964 Mar. 3 1965 Feb. 23
Baltimore Arts Festival 1976 June
Baltimore Hebrew Congregation 1968 Mar. 26
Baltimore Museum of Art 1950 Apr. 14 1953 May 20 1953 May 28 (typescript copy from Michel Fourney to BMA) 1953 Dec. 7 1953 Dec. 11 1954 Sept. 16 1955 Jan. 7 1955 Apr. 7 1958 Feb. 21 1958 July 22 1959 Sept. 8 1960 Feb. 11 1961 Feb. 10 1962 Feb. 14 1964 May 4 1964 Oct. 14 (carbon of typescript memo) 1964 Dec. 21 (to BMA from Sidney E. Cohn) 1966 Aug. 18 1967 Apr. 26 1968 June 6 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1968 June 9 1970 May 18 1970 Oct. 6 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1970 Dec. 31 1972 Feb. 14 1974 Aug. 9 1975 Jan. 6 (carbon of typescript memo) 1975 June 17 1975 Oct. 21 1976 Dec. 27 1977 Mar. 8 1977 Mar. 31 1977 Apr. 11 1977 Apr. 26 1977 May 26 (typescript carbon from David McIntyre to BMA) 1977 June 21 1977 Aug. 17 (Great Names in Baltimore campaign) 1977 Nov. 9 1977 Nov. 9 (to David McIntyre) 1977 Dec. 14
B. T. Batsford Ltd. (United Kingdom) 1945 Mar. 27
Benedictine Art Awards (New York) 1967 Apr. 6 1970 Jan. 27 1970 Jan. 31 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Bernstein, Ruth M. 1950s (?) 1970 Feb. 1972 Feb. 1 1972 Mar. 31 1972 May
Breeskin, Adelyn Dohme ("Mrs. B") 1950 Apr. 14 1953 May 20 1953 Dec. 11 1954 Sept. 16 1955 Jan. 7 1955 Apr. 7 1958 Feb. 21 1958 July 22 1959 Sept. 8 1950s (?) 1960 Feb. 11 1961 Feb. 10 1962 Feb. 14 1966 Sept. 8 1971 Jan. 14 1972 June 30 1976 Nov. 30
Brown, James L. 1976 June 1976 Nov. 13
Bryant, Robert ("Bob") 1966 Jan. 25 1966 Nov. 9 (photocopy to Baltimore Sun Papers) 1968 June 4 1970 June 1 1972 Apr. 19 1972 Apr. 25
Butler Institute of American Art (Youngstown) 1958 June 13 1958 June 28 1962 Apr. 6
Carlson, Carolyn Stout 1971 May 29 1972 June 1 1977 Sept. 28
Cashen, Elizabeth 1959 Nov. 8
Chautauqua Art Association (New York) 1961 July 7 (telegram)
College of Notre Dame of Maryland 1968 Oct. 23 1977 Mar. 27 1977 June 12 (2 letters)
Container Corporation of America (Chicago) 1949 Sept. 2 1951 Mar. 8
Corcoran Gallery of Art (Washington, D. C.) 1952 Nov. 13 1952 Nov. 18 1953 Oct. 21 1953 Nov. 21 1963 Nov. 22 1965 Oct. 26 1965 Nov. 12 (2 letters)
Cox, Shelby Shackelford and Dick See Shackelford, Shelby
Deene, Claire 1956 Dec. 12 1950s (?) 1961 Feb. 16 1963 Aug. 12 1965 May 4 (2 letters) 1965 May 18 1965 July 1 1966 July 24 1968 July 27 undated (fragment and letter)
Denver Art Museum 1948 July 7 1974 Dec. 19 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1974 Dec. 26
Erickson, Robert Wainwright 1944 (fragment) 1948 Feb. 14 1950s (?)
Essex Community College (Maryland) 1976 Oct. 12 1978 Apr. 5 1978 Apr. 10 1978 July 19 undated
Ford Foundation (New York) 1958 Oct. 22 1958 Nov. 25 1959 Feb. 4 1959 Apr. 24 1959 May 1 1959 May 20 1959 Sept. 28 1959 Nov. 16 1959 Dec. 10 1959 (?) 1960 Jan. 11 1960 Jan. 22
Foster, James W. 1953 Dec. 7 1957 Aug. 7 1962 Mar. 6 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1962 Mar. 26 1962 Nov. 5 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1963 Jan. 10 1963 Feb. 4 1960s (?) 1976 July 22 1976 Aug. 1 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1976 Aug. 19 1976 Dec. 2 1977 Mar. 10 1977 Oct. 6 undated
Freudenheim, Tom L. 1972 Feb. 14 1974 Aug. 9 1975 Jan. 6 (carbon of typescript memo) 1975 June 17 1976 Dec. 27 1977 May 11 1977 June 21 1977 Aug. 29 1977 Aug. 29 (to Dave McIntyre) 1977 Dec. 14
Gallery 100 (New Jersey) 1970 Feb. 11
Geisler, Ordella ("Giz") 1968 July 21 1968 Dec. 1 1969 Nov. 22 1970 Sept. 24 1970 Oct. 22
Goldstein, Gladys and Ed 1968
Gorski, Henry and Berni 1977 Aug. 22 1977 Oct. 15 undated
Goucher College (Maryland) 1960 Jan. 18 1960 Feb. 18 1963 Aug. 12 1978 July 27
Guillaume, David Flierl 1959 Oct. 12 1966 Nov. 1972 Oct. 9 (typescript carbon to Lowe Art Gallery, Syracuse University, with list of paintings) undated
Harford, Carol V. (Assistant for Cultural Affairs, The White House) 1969 Dec. 6
Hawkins, Erick 1950s (?) (3 letters) undated
Henkes, Robert 1971 Jan. 27 1971 Feb. 28
Hill, David 1944 (fragment) 1970 Dec. 10 1971 Mar. 16 (outgoing typescript carbon from David McIntyre) 1971 Mar. 23 1977 Sept. 12
Honolulu Academy of Arts 1976 July 22 1976 Aug. 1 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1976 Aug. 19 1976 Dec. 2 1977 Mar. 10 1977 Oct. 6
Idol, Ross 1967 Oct. 5
Jewish Community Center of Baltimore 1964 June 1 1972 Jan. 25 1972 Jan. 28 1973 Mar. 13 1973 Sept. 24 1973 Oct. 10 1978 June 8
Johnson, Lincoln F. 1960 Feb. 18 1963 Aug. 12 1976 Dec. 1
Juster Gallery (New York) 1960 Dec. 19
Kleff, Tomi 1970 May 1976 Nov.
Koch, Charlotte Rain and Edward 1969 Dec. 16 undated
Koch, John 1962 Dec. 11
Kuh, Katharine 1965 Mar. 18
Levy, Julien 1977 May 17
Lowry, Bates 1967 (?)
Lynch, Lawrence V. 1965 Dec. 20 1966 Feb. 23 1966 Mar. 14 (outgoing carbon mistakenly addressed to Thomas)
McIntyre, David 1959 Aug. 26 1964 May 4 1971 Mar. 16 (typescript carbon to David Hill) 1974 Mar. 7 (photocopy of typescript memo of resignation from Baltimore Museum of Art) 1974 Nov. 29 (typescript carbon to National Gallery of Art) 1977 May 26 (typescript carbon to Baltimore Museum of Art) 1977 Aug. 29 (from Tom L. Freudenheim) 1977 Nov. 9 (from Baltimore Museum of Art)
Macomber, William B. (U. S. Ambassador to Turkey) 1974 Sept. 30
Mazaroff, Stan 1977 Oct. 4
Menotti, Gian Carlo 1937 or 1938 1947 Sept. 3 1971 July 20 (outgoing holograph draft)
Meyerhoff, Jane undated
Miller, Mary Owings 1966 June 2
Miller & Paine (Lincoln, Nebraska) 1946 Apr. 9 1946 Nov. 14 1948 Feb. 9 1948 Oct. 28 1967 Feb. 9 1967 Feb. 20 1967 June 19 1969 Dec. 19 1970 Jan. 5 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1970 Jan. 26 1970 Feb. 1 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1970 Mar. 15 (from Claude Brommage) 1970 Apr. 23
Millet, Ralph T. 1972 June 28 1973 Jan. 1 1973 June 28 1973 July 11 1974 Jan. 1 1974 Dec. 1 (typescript carbon to National Gallery of Art) 1974 Dec. 8 (typescript carbon to National Gallery of Art) 1974 Dec. 11 (typescript carbon to National Gallery of Art) 1974 Dec. 11 (typescript photocopy from National Gallery of Art) undated
Morgan State College (Baltimore) 1971 Dec. 21 1972 Mar. 20 (typescript photocopy from Nationalgalerie to MSC)
National Brewing Co. (Baltimore) 1969 Apr. 10 (re: Land of Pleasant Living Regional Art Competition)
National Collection of Fine Arts (Smithsonian Institution) 1967 June 28 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1972 June 30 1972 Dec. 20
National Gallery of Art (Washington, D. C.) 1974 Nov. 12 1974 Nov. 16 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1974 Nov. 29 (typescript carbon from David McIntyre to NGA) 1974 Dec. 1 (typescript carbon from Ralph T. Millet to NGA) 1974 Dec. 3 (typescript carbon from Isabel Padro to NGA) 1974 Dec. 3 (typescript carbon from Martha J. Martin to NGA) 1974 Dec. 4 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1974 Dec. 8 (typescript carbon from Ralph T. Millet to NGA) 1974 Dec. 11 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1974 Dec. 11 (typescript carbon from Ralph T. Millet to NGA) 1974 Dec. 11 (typescript photocopy to Ralph T. Millet) 1974 Dec. 16 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1975 Apr. 25 (typescript photocopy from Isabel Padro to NGA) 1975 Apr. 25 (typescript photocopy from Martha J. Martin to NGA) 1975 Apr. 28 1975 May 12
Nationalgalerie (Berlin) 1972 Mar. 20 (typescript photocopy to Morgan State College) 1972 Apr. 10 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1972 May 9 1972 June 12 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1972 Aug. 28 (outgoing typescript carbon with shipping receipts) 1972 Sept. 19 1978 Oct. 2 (outgoing typescript photocopy to Neues Nationalgalerie)
Norfolk Museum (Virginia) 1961 Jan. 27 1961 Feb. 9
Oklahoma Printmakers Society 1963 Apr. 9
Ostryniec, Jane E. and Jim 1972 Apr. 12
Palijczuk, Wasyl 1967 June 27 1970 June 2 1972 Feb. 16
Palmer, Martin 1970 July 2 1971 Feb. 6 1971 Apr. 21 1971 Dec. 21 1971 Dec. 22 1972 Dec. 20
Parkhurst, Charles and Rima 1966 Aug. 18 1966 Nov. (Rima) 1967 Apr. 26 1967 June 28 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1968 June 9 1970 May 18 1970 Oct. 6 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1970 Dec. 31 1974 Nov. 12 1974 Nov. 16 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1974 Dec. 11 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1974 Dec. 16 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1975 Apr. 28 1975 May 12 1975 June 29
Peale Museum (Baltimore) 1957 Oct. 23
Peters, Louis B. 1961 Jan. 18
Petrick, Virginia 1968 Oct. 23 1977 Mar. 27
Phoenix-Chase Galleries (Baltimore) 1964 June 10 (Phoenix Galleries) 1972 July 14
Pitts, William Louis (Reverend) 1970 Sept. (invitation and letter) 1970 Dec. 1971 Mar. 6 1972 Mar. 17 1972 Aug. 31 1972 Sept. 10 1973 Sept. 10 1975 Jan. 24 1976 Dec. 3 1977 Aug. 22 1977 Sept. 6 (fragment) 1977 Sept. 14 1978 Sept. 12 undated (5)
Quisgard, Liz Whitney 1968 Dec. 20 (researching Baltimore Magazine article, "Baltimore's Top Twelve") 1968 Dec. 28 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Raydon Gallery (New York) 1971 June 21 1971 June 24 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Richardson, Brenda 1975 Oct. 21 1977 Mar. 8 1977 Mar. 31 1977 Apr. 11 1977 Apr. 26 1977 July 11 1977 Nov. 9 1977 Nov. 9 (to David McIntyre)
Rosenthal, Gertrude ("Trude") 1961 Jan. 29 1964 July 21 1964 Oct. 14 (carbon of typescript memo) 1964 Dec. 21 (Rosenthal's note on letter from Sidney E. Cohn) 1967 Aug. 24 (outgoing holograph) 1971 Oct. 5 1971 Dec. 7 1972 Apr. 20 1973 Apr. 1 (to Dave McIntyre) 1973 Apr. 23 1976 Sept. 14 undated (2)
Santa Barbara Museum of Art (California) 1962 Mar. 6 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1962 Mar. 26 1962 Nov. 5 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1963 Jan. 10 1963 Feb. 4
Sarasota Art Association (Florida) 1960 Apr. 2
Shackelford, Shelby 1977 Nov. 10
Shapiro, Lillian 1970 Apr. 5 1971 Feb. 14
Smith, Esther 1958 Nov. 8 (praise & poetry)
Society of the Four Arts (Palm Beach) 1959 Dec. 2 1960 Feb. 4 1962 Dec. 10 1965 Dec. 3 1970 Dec. 9 (outgoing typescript carbon to Mr. Baur regarding "Exhibition of American Paintings") 1970 Dec. 11 (outgoing typescript carbon)
Spencer, Eleanor Patterson 1971 Jan. 17 1977 Aug. 21 1977 Aug. 21 (to Dave McIntyre)
Taylor, Bertha Fanning 1953 Sept. 24 1953 Oct. 11 1954 Apr. 14
Taylor, Otis 1941 Sept. 29 1951 June 14 1953 Feb. 25 (fragment) 1955 Mar. 19 1950s (?) (2 letters) 1967 Jan. 21 1967 Apr. 5 1971 Feb. 13 1976 Mar. 19 1978 July 23 undated
Thirkield, Scout 1964 Aug. 7
Tidewater Artists (Norfolk) 1953 Sept. 24 1953 Oct. 11
Toklas, Alice B. 1933 Nov. 30 1935 Feb. 25
Tour Gallery (Albuquerque) 1962 Nov. 23 1963 Mar. 29 1963 Dec. 15
Tunis, Elizabeth and Edwin 1968 Mar. 9 1968 Oct. 1 1969 Aug. 3 1970 May 11 1970 July 6
Turner, Sally and Ted 1977 Oct. 30 undated
Tydings, Joseph D. (U. S. Senator) 1969 Nov. 25
Unger, Andy 1977 Oct. 6 1977 Oct. 6 (to Dave McIntyre)
Watkins, Ruth Nagle 1977 May 5 1977 June 12 (2 letters) 1977 Sept. 12
Wells, Betty 1966 Oct. 1967 Apr. 16 1967 June 1
Western Maryland College 1958 Nov. 8 1963 July 24 1964 Oct. 19 1972 Feb. 16 1972 Feb. 22 1977 Feb. 28
Whitney Museum of American Art (New York) 1960 Feb. 5 1966 Nov. 27 (outgoing typescript carbon) 1966 Dec. 7 1967 Jan. 31
Julius Wile Sons and Co., Inc. (New York) 1967 May 8 (re: Benedictine Art Awards)
Wilson, May 1964 Dec. 1 1965 Nov. 1
Zavadil, Florence 1965 Nov. 1968 May 19 1971 Jan.